Contact

blradhakrishnan@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ blradhakrishnan (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Cloud Computing
OpenStack
SUSE Cloud

Languages

English

Tamil

Malayalam

Certifications

VMware Data Center Virtualization Fundamentals

Certified OpenStack Administrator

GCP Essentials

SUSE Certified Administrator (SCA) in Enterprise Linux 12

SUSE Certified Engineer in Enterprise Linux 15

Honors-Awards

Effective use of Learning Management System (Moodle 2)

Publications

Securing Blockchain based Electronic Health Record using Multilevel Authentication

Fair service matching agent for federate d cloud

BL Radhakrishnan

Cloud Certifications(Google | OpenStack | SUSE OpenStack) | SUSE Certified Linux Engineer | Faculty | Trainer, KITS Coimbatore

Summary

11+ years of experience in IT operations, training and teaching. Good experience in Server, Cloud

deployments and administration. 4+ years of exclusive experience in OpenStack Cloud operations. Proven skills in problem solving to provide excellent user support. Instrumental in migrating legacy applications to the cloud.

Experience

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences

7 years 2 months

System Admin - SUSE Center of Excellence for Cloud Computing - Research Lab | Faculty

July 2013 - Present (7 years 2 months)

Coimbatore Area, India

Technical Knowledge

- # Cloud (Google | AWS | OpenStack)
- # SUSE Linux
- # Docker
- # VMware, KVM
- # Blockchain
- # Ansible
- # C++, Java and Python

Faculty

- # To teach undergraduate and graduate level subjects
- # Offer internal training
- # Instructor for SCA (SUSE Certified Administrator) and EMC Cloud Infrastructure and Services
- # Industry tie up and Collaborations
- # Member of Curriculum Development Cell and Board of Studies.

Coordinator Industry Academia Collabouration

July 2013 - Present (7 years 2 months)

Coimbatore Area, India

Anna University Affiliated Engineering College (MACET) Faculty

November 2008 - July 2013 (4 years 9 months)

Kanyakumari

- # VMware ESXi server, Linux web server and database server administration.
- # Teach undergraduate and graduate level subjects.
- # Evaluate the students in their class work, lab work, assignments and guide their projects.
- # Assist the students in placement activities and develop learning materials.

Education

Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences

Ph.D, Detection and Analysis of Sleep Disorders using IOT and Data Analytics (2018 - 2022)

Dr. MGR University

Master of Technology (M.Tech.), Computer Science and Engineering · (2007 - 2008)

Anna University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Engineering (2003 - 2006)

MG Polytechnic Nagercoil

Diploma in Computer Technology, Computer Engineering · (2001 - 2003)